<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Venus</title>
	<atom:link href="https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie</link>
	<description>The Beauty Store</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 08:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to get clear skin?</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-get-clear-skin/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-get-clear-skin/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 10:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone would like to have flawless skin, it not only looks beautiful, but it makes you feel great and super confident too. The main things that can help you get clear skin revolve around a healthy diet, drinking plenty of water and keeping up with a regular skin care regime. There are also a number [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone would like to have flawless skin, it not only looks beautiful, but it makes you feel great and super confident too. The main things that can help you get clear skin revolve around a healthy diet, drinking plenty of water and keeping up with a regular skin care regime. There are also a number of extra steps you can take to keep your skin clear that you may not have heard about. Here ten of those little tricks you can use that will help you get a clear complexion.</p>
<p><b>1. Improve skin texture with papaya</b></p>
<p>Papaya contains an enzyme that will fight bacteria on the skin and help reduce inflammation. It also has a mild bleaching effect, so papaya will lighten skin and help to fade scars and blemishes. To make a skin rejuvenating mask with papaya, mash up the flesh of one ripe papaya and stir in a tablespoon of honey. Apply the mixture to your face and leave it to sit for half an hour.</p>
<p><b>2. Keep it clean</b></p>
<p>Another good tip on how to get clear skin is to wash your face twice a day with a mild cleanser and, of course, always remove your makeup before you go to bed. If you dont keep your face clean, your pores will become blocked and you could get infections, or breakouts. Keep your hands away from your face during the day as well, or you will transfer to dirt and bacteria onto your skin.</p>
<p><b>3. Balance the PH of your skin with baking soda</b></p>
<p>One of great tips on how to get clear skin is to use baking soda, it makes a great exfoliating ingredient that will balance the PH of your skin and it also antiseptic and inflammatory properties. Mix a teaspoon of baking soda with some liquid coconut oil and some lemon juice to form a paste and then gently exfoliate your skin with the mixture. Do this twice a week, and it will keep your skin free of dead skin cells and keep it looking fresh.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Exfoliate with strawberries</b></p>
<p>Strawberries are another natural ingredient that makes a really effective exfoliator. Mash up some strawberries and mix in an equal part of natural plain yoghurt in with them. Massage that mixture gently into your skin and then leave it to sit for ten minutes before you wash it off with warm water. Then, pat dry your face and moisturise.</p>
<p><b>5. Moisturise with honey</b></p>
<p>To keep skin clear you need to keep it well moisturised and honey is a wonderful natural moisturiser that also has antibacterial properties that will keep breakouts at bay. Apply raw honey to your skin and leave it on for twenty minutes and, when you wash it off again with lukewarm water, your skin will be hydrated and feel really soft and smooth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-get-clear-skin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to find a perfect lipstick for your skin tone?</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-find-a-perfect-lipstick-for-your-skin-tone/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-find-a-perfect-lipstick-for-your-skin-tone/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 09:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=277</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you ever thought that there must be a more scientific way to choose lipstick than just choosing the same shade you chose before, or grabbing a colour that looks good in the store and then trying out at home? While we dont believe that there are any hard and fast rules to makeup, there [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever thought that there must be a more scientific way to choose lipstick than just choosing the same shade you chose before, or grabbing a colour that looks good in the store and then trying out at home? While we dont believe that there are any hard and fast rules to makeup, there are some guidelines that you could follow that would help you select a shade of lipstick that will suit you. Here are ten tips to help you find the shade of lipstick that is most likely to compliment your skin tone.</p>
<p><b>1. Know what your skin undertone is</b></p>
<p>You need to know what type of complexion you have, and what your skin undertone is. You may already know this, because it is also helpful for when you are choosing foundation. The easiest way to tell if you have a warm, or a cool skin undertone, is to look at the colour of the veins in your wrists. If they have a bluish tinge, then you have a cool undertone and, if they appear to have a green tinge, then your skin undertone is warm.</p>
<p><b>2. Cool Vs Warm skin undertone</b></p>
<p>As a very general guide, if you have a warm skin undertone, then colours like pink and purple will suite you. If you have a cool skin undertone, then they richer colours like berries and plums might suit you better.</p>
<p><b>3. Daytime lipstick</b></p>
<p>When you are choosing a lipstick, dont forget that you will probably need different shades for different occasions. Most likely, you will have at least one subtle shade for day wear and a more dramatic, bold shade for the evenings. The easiest way to choose a lipstick that wont be too over the top for work is to choose a shade that is just two or three steps up from the natural colour of your skin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-find-a-perfect-lipstick-for-your-skin-tone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing beauty hacks that you need to try</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/amazing-beauty-hacks-that-you-need-to-try/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/amazing-beauty-hacks-that-you-need-to-try/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 09:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=269</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When time is short and you need to get ready fast, a girl needs a good list of beauty hacks and tips to see her through. You cant always guarantee to have the right product or tool to hand, just when you need it, so sometimes we have to improvise and make do. We all [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When time is short and you need to get ready fast, a girl needs a good list of beauty hacks and tips to see her through. You cant always guarantee to have the right product or tool to hand, just when you need it, so sometimes we have to improvise and make do. We all love hacks and tips that make life a bit simpler, so here are ten amazing beauty hacks that you really should try.</p>
<p><b>1. Treat a pimple with a dab of Greek yoghurt</b></p>
<p>If you dab a little bit of Greek yoghurt on a pimple and leave it in for about twenty minutes, it will reduce the inflation and help to unclog the pore. Greek yoghurt has anti-inflammatory properties that will reduce the redness and it contains lactic acid that will break down dead skin cells that could be whats blocking the pore and causing the pimple.</p>
<p><b>2. Make eyeshadow pop with whitepencil</b></p>
<p>To make an eyeshadow look more like the colour that you saw on the packaging, run a white eyepencil over your eyelid before you apply the eyeshadow. It creates the perfect base for the eyeshadow and it will even make sheer or the less heavily pigmented eyeshadows pop.</p>
<p><b>3. Use a teaspoon to keep mascara off your eyelids</b></p>
<p>To stop bits of mascara getting on your eyelids, hold a teaspoon over your eyelid, so it hugs right up against your eye. Then, you can sweep with the mascara brush and any excess mascara will go onto the back of the spoon and not onto your lids.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Use a chapstick on a sore nose</b></p>
<p>A chapstick works just as well on a sore nose as it does on your lips. The next time you catch a cold and your nose gets sore, try rubbing your chapstick on it and youll find that it does a wonderful of job of moisturising the dry skin and it eases the pain. Its a lot less greasy than something like Vaseline too.</p>
<p><b>5. Brighten up tired looking eyes with a touch of white</b></p>
<p>The easiest way to open up tired eyes and to give them a wide-awake look is to apply a small amount of white eyeliner, just to the corners of your eyes. It will brighten up your eyes and make the rest of your makeup look more noticeable too. No one will ever know you only got three hours of sleep the night before.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/amazing-beauty-hacks-that-you-need-to-try/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to make makeup look natural?</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-make-makeup-look-natural/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-make-makeup-look-natural/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 09:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=264</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The whole point of natural looking makeup is to make it look light and effortless, but its actually quite a hard look to perfect and, in trying to make it like you have no makeup on at all, you may well have to use more makeup than you would have thought. Heavy, bold makeup can [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The whole point of natural looking makeup is to make it look light and effortless, but its actually quite a hard look to perfect and, in trying to make it like you have no makeup on at all, you may well have to use more makeup than you would have thought. Heavy, bold makeup can look great for the evenings and it also works better in the winter, but as we approach the spring, a lighter, more natural look tends to go better with the light colours and pastels of that at time of year. Apparently, the guys like the natural look too, so here are ten great tips on how to make makeup look more natural.</p>
<p><b>1. Know what colours suit you</b></p>
<p>Before we even get into the application of natural looking makeup; a few words on the importance of knowing what colours suit you. For makeup to look natural, it needs to compliment your skin tone, not clash with it. If you have pale skin, then peaches and pinks will work for you and if you have dark skin, beiges and creams will suit you better. Test your makeup before you buy it and make sure that the colours dont stand out too much against your skin.</p>
<p><b>2. Take care of your skin</b></p>
<p>The fewer blemishes and dry patches of skin you have, the less makeup you will need, so take good care of your skin and keep up with your regular skin care regime. Always remove all your makeup every night before you go to bed, cleanse your skin thoroughly, moisturise regularly, and exfoliate your skin once a week to remove the dead skin cells.</p>
<p><b>3. Dont mask your face with foundation</b></p>
<p>Another good tip on how to make makeup look natural is to avoid masking your face with foundation. The aim of natural looking makeup is to create a flawless look, but doing so without making it look too obvious that you are wearing makeup. Rather than covering your whole face with foundation, try using concealer on only those areas of skin that need a bit of coverage, like red patches, or dark areas of skin. Use concealer sparingly too, so that it just covers any blemishes, but still looks natural.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. An alternative to foundation</b></p>
<p>Here is another great tip on how to make makeup look natural: if you really feel that you need foundation, try using a tinted moisturiser instead, or you could add a few drops of your foundation to your face moisturiser and get a bit of colour coverage that way. This will still give you coverage and even out your skin tone, but it will look a lot smoother and a lot more natural than a heavy application of foundation would.</p>
<p><b>5. Add a touch of colour</b></p>
<p>To give yourself a healthy glow, apply a small amount blush to your cheeks. Use a shade that closely matches your natural glow and apply it sparingly. Apply blush to the apples of your cheeks first and then blend it upwards, towards your cheekbones, until there is no noticeable edge to it. The look you are trying to achieve is the same as you would look right after you have been for short run; glowing and healthy.</p>
<p><b>6. Skip the eyeliner</b></p>
<p>Heavy eyeliner and bold eyeshadows are not what you are looking for if you want to achieve the effortless, natural look, so our next tip onhow to make makeup look natural is to skip both altogether and concentrate and making your lashes look great. If you do want to use eyeliner, concentrate on using it to make your lashes look thicker. Apply a very thin line, as close to your lash line as possible, and that will have the effect of making your lashes look thicker, but without making you look too made up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-make-makeup-look-natural/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to look after your skin in cold weather?</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-look-after-your-skin-in-cold-weather/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-look-after-your-skin-in-cold-weather/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 09:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=261</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What with the bitterly cold winds when you are out and then the drying effect that your central heating at home has, its no wonder that so many people suffer with dry skin in the cold weather. For some people, winter dry skin is no more than an irritation, but for others, it can cause [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What with the bitterly cold winds when you are out and then the drying effect that your central heating at home has, its no wonder that so many people suffer with dry skin in the cold weather. For some people, winter dry skin is no more than an irritation, but for others, it can cause the skin to crack and become really sore. If you struggle with dry skin every autumn and winter, read these ten tips that will show you how to look after your skin in the cold weather.</p>
<p><b>1. Protect your hands</b></p>
<p>The skin on your hands is more prone to drying out because, not only are your hands exposed to the elements all day long, the skin on your hands is quite thin, compared to the rest of your body and it produces less natural oils. Prevention is always better than a cure, so wear gloves whenever you go out in the cold weather; its the simplest way to protect them.</p>
<p><b>2. Dont forget the sunscreen</b></p>
<p>Just because its cold out, that doesnt mean that the sun isnt shining and, on cold, clear days, the UV rays from the sun will still damage your skin if you dont protect it. Apply a broad spectrum sunscreen to both your hands and your face every day and top it up, if you are going to be outdoors for a long time.</p>
<p><b>3. Bathe in lukewarm water</b></p>
<p>A scolding hot bath or shower may feel great after a day outside in the cold, but it will play havoc with your skin. Very hot water breaks down the natural oily protective layer that your skin has and dries out the skin. So, bathe, shower, and wash, in lukewarm water. If your skin has become dry and itchy, add a little baking soda to your bath water for some relief.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Moisturise twice a day</b></p>
<p>Your skin will need more moisture in the cold weather, so moisturise every morning, every night, and after a bath or shower and every time you wash your hands. Dont wait until you have dry skin, start your extra moisturising as soon as the cold weather closes in. Coconut oil is very good for this purpose. If you keep the moisture in your skin topped up all the time, your skin wont dry out in the first place.</p>
<p><b>5. Keep yourself well hydrated from the inside</b></p>
<p>When it is cold, we tend to drink less and, when we do drink, we usually drink hot beverages like tea, coffee or hot chocolate. Your need for water, though, is no less in the winter than it is in the summer, so keep up with the good water drinking habits you developed in the summer and that will keep your skin hydrated from the inside. If you dont feel like drinking cold water, try some warm water with some honey and lemon instead.</p>
<p><b>6. Exfoliate</b></p>
<p>Its easy to forget exfoliating in the winter because you spend most of the time covered up, but not exfoliating can actually make a dry skin problem worse. If you let the dead skin cells build up, they can attract and hold water, which will then cause irritation and even more drying out of the skin. Exfoliate your hands, lips and face regularly during the cold weather and it will help keep your skin looking healthy and it will allow your moisturiser to soak in better.</p>
<p><b>7. Use a humidifier</b></p>
<p>Central heating dries all the moisture out of the air and that, in turn, will dry out your skin. Use a humidifier in your home, especially in your bedroom. It will replace some of that lost moisture in the air and prevent your skin drying out. The best thing to do is several humidifiers, one in each room that you spend the most time in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/how-to-look-after-your-skin-in-cold-weather/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Beauty Secrets Of All Pretty Girls</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-beauty-secrets-of-all-pretty-girls/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-beauty-secrets-of-all-pretty-girls/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 11:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=110</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Very often, the best beauty secrets are the simplest ones; the ones that are passed down from mother to daughter, or shared between friends. These arent really tips that anyone has been deliberately hiding from you, they are just tips that the girls who know them, thought that you already knew as well. Here are [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Very often, the best beauty secrets are the simplest ones; the ones that are passed down from mother to daughter, or shared between friends. These arent really tips that anyone has been deliberately hiding from you, they are just tips that the girls who know them, thought that you already knew as well. Here are ten of those beauty secrets that the pretty girls never thought to tell you about.</p>
<p><b>1. Dry brush before you shower</b></p>
<p>Everyone has heard about dry brushing, but how many of you have actually tried it? Theres no magic technique to dry brushing. Its really simple to do and it can have a remarkable effect on your skin. Before you shower, just take a body brush and gently brush your body, in short strokes, in the direction of your heart. It boosts circulation, exfoliates the skin, and it is said that dry brushing also stimulates the lymphatic system and helps your body detox itself. What it will certainly do, is it will leave you with amazingly smooth skin.</p>
<p><b>2. Exfoliate your lips</b></p>
<p>You will never be able to get smooth and perfect looking lipstick if you have dry, flaky skin on your lips, so dont forget that your lips need exfoliating just like the rest of your skin does. So, if you have ever wondered why some girls have soft and smooth looking lips, the secret is in the exfoliation. There is no need for any special scrubs to do this. Simply apply some lip balm to your lips and then gently scrub them with a clean toothbrush. Dont apply too much pressure, though, you only want to remove the dead flakes of skin, not rub your lips red raw.</p>
<p><b>3. Contour to create shape</b></p>
<p>Contouring is something that a lot of people think is really hard to do, but its a lot simpler than you may have thought. Sure, you may have to practice it a few times before you perfect it, but we guarantee you will love what it can do for your features. If you apply just a single tone of foundation to your face, it has the effect of flattening out your features, so try using a highlighter on the partsof your face that would naturally catch the light and that will make your features look more pronounced.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Go easy with the blush</b></p>
<p>Remember that when you are applying blush, the aim is to create a natural looking glow. A lot of people overdo blush and the end result looks anything but natural and, in the worst cases, almost clown-like. Less is often best when it comes to makeup, so apply blush sparingly, starting about the width of two fingers away from your nose and apply it only to the apples of your cheeks. Remember to blend it in as well and then it will look a lot more natural.</p>
<p><b>5. Dot your eyeliner on</b></p>
<p>If your hands arent too, drawing in eyeliner in a perfectly straight line can be more than just a bit of a challenge. You can make applying gel eyeliner a lot easier to do if you hold the pen horizontally to your eye and then dot on the eyeliner in three or four separate lines. Its a lot easier than trying to draw one long continuous line.</p>
<p><b>6. Take care of those brows</b></p>
<p>They might be only small, but your brows can really let you down if you dont take good care of them. Keep them neat and well plucked, but dont pluck them every single day, or you will eventually end up with no brows at all. Remember that you can keep your brows healthy and encourage growth by conditioning them, just like you do the hair on your head. Try applying some castor oil, olive oil or sweet almond oil on your brows and see what a difference it makes.</p>
<p><b>7. Turn down the heat when you shower</b></p>
<p>A scalding hot shower at the end of a hard day at work feels great, but it really is no good for your skin at all. Very hot showers strip all the natural oils out of your skin and it will leave your skin feeling tight and dry. It can also cause other skin problems, like breakouts, because you will moisturise your dry skin and then your body will also produce more oils to combat the dry skin.</p>
<p><b>8. Start going green</b></p>
<div></div>
<p>One thing that you will always find in a pretty girls kitchen is a juicer. You already know how important it is to eat a healthy diet and drink plenty of water, but if you add some green juices to your regular diet, it does wonders for your skin. Use ingredients like green apples, kale, cucumber, and parsley to make delicious and nutritious green juices and you will soon see an amazing glow to your skin.</p>
<p><b>9. Find your shade</b></p>
<p>A big mistake that quite a lot of people make with makeup is that they use the wrong shade of foundation and they get a noticeable line between their face and their neck. When you are buying foundation, test it in your jaw line and test it when you are in natural light. That will give you a good idea of how well the colour of the foundation will match the skin on your neck.</p>
<p><b>10. Dont be afraid to use oil on your skin</b></p>
<p>Over-cleaning your skin can actually make oily skin worse, so dont be afraid to use oil to cleanse your skin and remove makeup. Natural oils, such as olive oil and coconut oil, are very good for removing makeup and they moisturise and nourish your skin too.</p>
<p>What are your best beauty tips?</p>
<p>Stay beautiful!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-beauty-secrets-of-all-pretty-girls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Way To Get Clearer Skin</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-way-to-get-clearer-skin/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-way-to-get-clearer-skin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 10:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=112</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone would like to have flawless skin, it not only looks beautiful, but it makes you feel great and super confident too. The main things that can help you get clear skin revolve around a healthy diet, drinking plenty of water and keeping up with a regular skin care regime. There are also a number [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone would like to have flawless skin, it not only looks beautiful, but it makes you feel great and super confident too. The main things that can help you get clear skin revolve around a healthy diet, drinking plenty of water and keeping up with a regular skin care regime. There are also a number of extra steps you can take to keep your skin clear that you may not have heard about. Here ten of those little tricks you can use that will help you get a clear complexion.</p>
<p><b>1. Improve skin texture with papaya</b></p>
<p>Papaya contains an enzyme that will fight bacteria on the skin and help reduce inflammation. It also has a mild bleaching effect, so papaya will lighten skin and help to fade scars and blemishes. To make a skin rejuvenating mask with papaya, mash up the flesh of one ripe papaya and stir in a tablespoon of honey. Apply the mixture to your face and leave it to sit for half an hour.</p>
<p><b>2. Keep it clean</b></p>
<p>Another good tip on how to get clear skin is to wash your face twice a day with a mild cleanser and, of course, always remove your makeup before you go to bed. If you dont keep your face clean, your pores will become blocked and you could get infections, or breakouts. Keep your hands away from your face during the day as well, or you will transfer to dirt and bacteria onto your skin.</p>
<p><b>3. Balance the PH of your skin with baking soda</b></p>
<p>One of great tips on how to get clear skin is to use baking soda, it makes a great exfoliating ingredient that will balance the PH of your skin and it also antiseptic and inflammatory properties. Mix a teaspoon of baking soda with some liquid coconut oil and some lemon juice to form a paste and then gently exfoliate your skin with the mixture. Do this twice a week, and it will keep your skin free of dead skin cells and keep it looking fresh.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Exfoliate with strawberries</b></p>
<p>Strawberries are another natural ingredient that makes a really effective exfoliator. Mash up some strawberries and mix in an equal part of natural plain yoghurt in with them. Massage that mixture gently into your skin and then leave it to sit for ten minutes before you wash it off with warm water. Then, pat dry your face and moisturise.</p>
<p><b>5. Moisturise with honey</b></p>
<p>To keep skin clear you need to keep it well moisturised and honey is a wonderful natural moisturiser that also has antibacterial properties that will keep breakouts at bay. Apply raw honey to your skin and leave it on for twenty minutes and, when you wash it off again with lukewarm water, your skin will be hydrated and feel really soft and smooth.</p>
<p><b>6. Use sunscreen every day</b></p>
<p>Another good tip on how to get clear skin is to use sunscreen. Sunscreen is not just for days at the beach, you should be using it every single day. Protect your skin from the harmful rays of the sun by applying a light, oil free, sunscreen every day. Shop around, and you will find that there are sunscreens for all skin types available, so they wont feel heavy on your skin or clog up your pores.</p>
<p><b>7. Lighten skin with lemon juice</b></p>
<p>Lemon juice can do wonders for the complexion. The critic acid in lemon juice removes dead skin cells and keeps the pores clean and the Vitamin C helps promote the growth of new skin cells. Lemon juice also has a mild bleaching effect, so it will lighten dark areas of skin and any blemishes. Simply apply fresh lemon juice to the skin and leave it to sit for ten minutes.</p>
<p><b>8. Change your pillowcase regularly</b></p>
<div></div>
<p>Anything that comes into contact with your face could have germs and dirt on it, so its important that you change your pillowcases regularly and clean your phone regularly too. If you dont, grime and bacteria can build up on them and that will cause breakouts and, potentially, other skin infections.</p>
<p><b>9. Reduce inflammation with turmeric</b></p>
<p>Another wonderful tip on how to get clear skin is to use turmeric. Turmeric is an age old skin treatment that will fight infection and help to reduce the appearance of scars and blemishes. For the best results, mix a tablespoon of turmeric powder with pineapple juice until you have a smooth paste. Apply the paste to your face and leave it on until it has dried, then wash off the dried paste with lukewarm water.</p>
<p><b>10. Hydrate skin with cucumber</b></p>
<p>Cucumbers are very good for the skin too. They contain ingredients that act as an astringent and so they will tone the skin as well as hydrate it very effectively. All you need to do is to cut some fairly thick slices of cucumber and then rub the slices over your face. When you are finished, you will find that your skin is lovely and soft and you will have a beautiful, radiant glow.</p>
<p>How to get clearskin? What are your best tips?</p>
<p>Stay beautiful!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/10-way-to-get-clearer-skin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Makeup rules that are worth breaking</title>
		<link>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/7-makeup-tips-that-nobody-told-you-about/</link>
		<comments>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/7-makeup-tips-that-nobody-told-you-about/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 14:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brian]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/?p=1</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Most rules in life that we have to follow are there for a good reason. Rules are there to keep us safe and to stop us harming other people and so, we all do, or should, stop at red lights, for example. Makeup rules, however, are rules that have been invented by someone who thinks [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most rules in life that we have to follow are there for a good reason. Rules are there to keep us safe and to stop us harming other people and so, we all do, or should, stop at red lights, for example. Makeup rules, however, are rules that have been invented by someone who thinks they know what will look best on us and what we will like. Makeup rules are great, if you use them for guidance and for ideas, but makeup is a very individual and personal thing, so not all rules have to be followed to the letter. If no one ever broke the makeup rules, then wed never have any new ideas, so take a look at these ten makeup rules that are worth breaking.</p>
<p><b>1. Your foundation should match your neck</b></p>
<p>This is one rule that we have seen that really doesnt make a lot of sense. Your face and your neck are usually different shades naturally, because more sun gets on your face than your neck. Whats more important is to not have a stark line between your face and your neck, which would look completely unnatural, so blend foundation, whatever the shade, so there is no discernible line between your chin and your neck.</p>
<p><b>2. Always pair smoky eyes with nude lips</b></p>
<p>The traditional advice is that just one, or the other, of your eyes or lips should be the focus of attention, so with smoky eyes, you should have nude lips. There is, of course, no reason why you cant have both bold lips and bold eyes, so long as you dont go over the top. In some ways, very bold eyes and nude lips can make it look like you didnt get time to finish your makeup!</p>
<p><b>3. Your nails and lips should always match</b></p>
<p>Using identical shades of nail polish and lipstick was a rule that held fast for many generations, up until around the sixties. Identical shades look old fashioned and too formal for today, so go for colours that complement each other, not necessarily those that match.</p>
<div></div>
<p><b>4. Always use a primer</b></p>
<p>A primer is great for smoothing the skin, but you dont need to use a primer every day, especially if you have dry skin. On most days, a moisturiser is all you will need and you can save the primer for special occasions, if you want to.</p>
<p><b>5. Never go out without makeup</b></p>
<p>This is another old rule that some women used to follow; theyd never leave home without putting their face on first. Of course, you can go out without any makeup on at all, or just a little bit, if you prefer, its all about whatever makes you feel comfortable, thats what matters. A few days, makeup-free, will let the air get to your skin and it could improve your complexion.</p>
<p><b>6. Never wear mascara or eyeliner on your bottom lashes</b></p>
<p>Some people insist that eyeliner and mascara on your bottom lashes will make you look older, but we dont think so. It is true, that if you have deep set eyes, or very small eyes, then leaving the bottom lashes nude can make eyes look bigger, but otherwise, there is no reason at all why you shouldnt use mascara and eyeliner all around your eyes.</p>
<p><b>7. Products should only be used for what they were intended</b></p>
<p>When it comes to what you use your products for, double or triple duty products can be of great help when you are in a hurry, or you run out of something. The only thing that you do need to be careful about is that you check the labels before you use anything near your eyes, just in case they arent suitable for that.</p>
<p><b>8. The more you spend, the better the makeup</b></p>
<div></div>
<p>The very, very, cheap makeup might not be high quality, but that doesnt mean that you have to spend a fortune on makeup. If you like it, then wear it, should be the rule of makeup, and if you spend big money on big brands, more often than not, you are paying for the name on the label, not for the ingredients.</p>
<p><b>9. Always apply concealer before foundation</b></p>
<p>This is another makeup rule that some women just find impractical to follow, because, if you apply your foundation first, then you can see what areas of skin have not been covered properly by the foundation and you can then apply concealer, just in those areas of skin that really need it.</p>
<p><b>10. Always let mascara dry before you apply a second coat</b></p>
<p>Like all these, so called, makeup rules, it comes down to personal preference. Many people find it easier to apply a second coat of mascara while the first coat has still not dried. They find it easier to work and shape the lashes when the first coat is still a bit wet and more flexible.</p>
<p>Do you like to break makeup rules?</p>
<p>Stay beautiful!</p>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://briancosie.github.io/classycosie/7-makeup-tips-that-nobody-told-you-about/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
